Finding Aids to Personal Papers and Special Collections in the VMFA Archives Willie Anne Wright Artist Archives, 1958-2003 VA-02
VMFA Archives, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts
Willie Anne Wright Artist Archives
1958-2003
VMFA Archives
Wright, Willie Anne
VA-02
2.5 Linear Feet 2 boxes; 172 folders
The collection documents the career of renowned lensless photographer Willie Anne Wright. Wright's paintings, serigraphs and drawings were her professional focus until 1972 when pinhole photography became her primary creative medium. Comprised mainly of the exhibition files Wright maintained, as well as information about gallery representation and art sales, the collection traces the evolution of her artistic journey over four decades.
Box VA-02 Box 1
Box VA-02 Box 2
Provenance
The collection was donated to the VMFA Archives by Willie Anne Wright in August 2016.
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Willie Anne Wright is a native and resident of Richmond, Virginia. She received a BS in Psychology from The College of William and Mary and an MFA in Painting from Virginia Commonwealth University. She also studied photography at Maine Photographic Workshops, Rockport, Maine; Visual Studies Workshops, Rochester, New York; and VCU.
Wright's paintings, serigraphs and drawings were her professional focus until 1972 when pinhole photography became her primary creative medium. Since then her lensless photography, pinhole and photogram, have been exhibited nationally and internationally, and have been included among numerous publications such as "Art News," "The Oxford American," "Le Stenope," and "The Book of Alternative Processes."
Wright's works are collected privately and publicly, and are in the permanent collections of Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, Richmond, Virginia; Chrysler Museum of Art, Norfolk, Virginia; George Eastman House, Rochester, New York; High Museum of Art, Atlanta Georgia; The Mariners' Museum, Newport News, Virginia; Southeast Museum of Photography, Daytona Beach, Florida; New Orleans Museum of Art, New Orleans, Louisiana; Mobile Museum of Art, Mobile, Alabama; Morris Museum of Art, Augusta, Georgia; New Mexico History Museum, Santa Fe, New Mexico; Longwood University, Farmville, Virginia; University of Mary Washington, Fredericksburg, Virginia; University of Maine, Bangor, Maine; and University of New Hampshire, Dublin, New Hampshire.
(The above information was taken from the website "Willie Anne Wright: Lensless Photography.")
Scope and Content Note
The collection's inclusive dates are 1958-2003, with the bulk of the material dating from 1964-2003. The collection is comprised of correspondence, checklists, invitations, posters, handbills, photographs, publications, press clippings, and other manuscript material.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into three series, and items are arranged chronologically within each series.
Series 1
Exhibition Files, 1964-2003
Series 2
Sales and Representation, 1980-2003
Series 3
Curriculum Vitae and Press, 1958-2003
Related Materials - VMFA Library: Catalogs
The Pinhole Image, Eleven Photographers, 1982
My Lensless Imaging: Pinhole Photographs and Photograms: 1972-2002, 2003
The Fleeting Glimpse: Selections in Modern and Contemporary Photography from the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 2010
Direct Positive, 2015
Related Materials - VMFA Library: Exhibition Files
Exhibition File: Virginia Artist: Willie Anne Wright, 1967
Exhibition File: Virginia Artist: Willie Anne Wright, 1971
Exhibition File: Virginia Artist One-man Exhibitions [Willie Anne Wright, David Diller], 1977
Exhibition File: Virginia Artists' Portfolio, 1980
Exhibition File: The Pinhole Image: Eleven Photographers, 1982
Exhibition File: Civil War Redux: Pinhole Photographs of Re-enactments, 2011
Exhibition File: Fleeting Glimpse: Selections of Modern and Contemporary Photography from the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 2011
Related Materials - VMFA Library: Artist File
Artist File: Willie Anne Wright
Related Materials - VMFA Library: Digital Collection
Willie Anne Wright Artist Archive Timeline
Photography, Pinhole; Photography, Artistic -- Exhibitions; Photography, Artistic; Photography, Pinhole -- Exhibitions; Photography--History--20th century; Photography--History--20th century -- Exhibitions; Photography--History--21st century; Photography--History--21st century -- Exhibitions
- Series 1: Exhibition Files, 1964-2003; VA-02-01
  Boxes 1-2 (159 Folders): This series is comprised of exhibition files for both solo and group shows that Wright participated in from 1964 to 2003. If no city is listed, then the location was Richmond. Wright also kept "miscellaneous" files for each decade as well as information about lectures, symposiums, and other events in which she participated.
  - Jewish Community Center, 1964 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
  - Midtown Gallery, 1965 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
  - Twentieth Century Gallery, Williamsburg, 1965-1967 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
  - Westhampton College, 1966 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 4)
  - Robinson House, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1967 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
  - University Theatre, Charlottesville, 1967 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 6)
  - Virginia Artists, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1969 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 7)
  - Fredericksburg Gallery of Art, Fredericksburg, 1969 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 8)
  - Windsor Gallery, 1969 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 10)
  - American Painting, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1970 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 11)
  - Limestone College, Gaffney, 1970 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 12)
  - Robinson House, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1970 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 13)
  - Westhampton College, 1970 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 14)
  - Thalhimer's First Virginia/North Carolina Invitational, 1970 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 15)
  - Twentieth Century Gallery, Williamsburg, 1970 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 16)
  - Mary Baldwin College, Staunton, 1971 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 17)
  - Virginia State College, Petersburg, 1971 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 18)
  - Virginia Artists, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1971 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 19)
  - Anderson Gallery, Virginia Commonwealth University, 1972 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 20)
  - Current Scene Gallery, Charlottesville, 1972 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 21)
  - Virginia Photographers, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1973 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 22)
  - Sharon Bennett Gallery, Atlanta, 1973 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 23)
  - Exhibition 280, Huntington Galleries, Huntington, 1974 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 24)
  - Southeastern Center for Contemporary Art, Winston-Salem, 1974 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 25)
  - Limestone College, Gaffney, 1974 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 26)
  - Prints – Four Women from Richmond, Fredericksburg Gallery of Art, Fredericksburg, 1974 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 27)
  - Paperworks, Washington Gallery, Georgetown, 1974 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 28)
  - Virginia Artists, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1975 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 29)
  - Virginia Photographers, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1975 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 30)
  - Foundry Gallery, Washington, D.C., 1975 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 31)
  - Carriage House Gallery, 1975 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 32)
  - Columbia Museum of Arts and Science, Columbia, 1975 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 33)
  - Juried Artists, Northern Virginia Fine Arts Association, The Athenaeum, Alexandria, 1975 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 34)
  - Willie Anne Wright Pinhole Photographs, Virginia Museum State Services, 1975-1987 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 35)
  - Virginia Beach Art Center, Virginia Beach, 1976 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 36)
  - Southeastern Center for Contemporary Art, Winston-Salem, 1978 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 37)
  - Recent Work by Willie Anne Wright, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1977 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 38)
  - Deja Vue Gallery, Toronto, 1977 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 39)
  - Virginia Intermont College, Bristol, 1978 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 40)
  - Art and the Photographic Image, Scott-McKennis Gallery, 1978-1979 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 41)
  - Photographers Invitational, Colorado Institute of Art, Denver, 1979 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 42)
  - Randolph-Macon College, Ashland, 1979 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 43)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority, Tennessee Valley Authority Washington Visitors Center, Washington, D.C., 1979 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 44)
  - Federated Arts Council of Richmond Invitational Exhibition, 1979 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 45)
  - Deja Vue Gallery, Toronto, 1979 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 47)
  - Women Photographers – Six from Virginia, Portsmouth Community Arts Center, Portsmouth, 1980 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 48)
  - Women, Image, Nature, Tyler School of Art, Temple University, Elkins Park, 1980 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 49)
  - Inaugural Exhibition, Virginia Beach Art Center, Virginia Beach, 1980 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 50)
  - Virginia Photographers, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1980 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 51)
  - Virginia Artists Portfolio, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1981-1994 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 52)
  - 2nd Street Gallery, Charlottesville, 1981-1985 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 53)
  - Portfolio, Richmond Printmaking Workshop, 1981 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 54)
  - Virginia Arts for Coleman, Reynolds/Minor Gallery, 1981 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 55)
  - Virginia Prints and Drawings, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1981 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 56)
  - Virginia Artists – Small Affordable Work, Activities – Lecture, Juror, Newsletter Article, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Blacksburg, 1981-1982 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 57)
  - American Set-ups, Wright State University, Dayton, 1981 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 58)
  - New Photographs, Anderson Gallery, 1982 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 59)
  - Photospiva '82, Joplin, 1982 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 60)
  - The Pinhole Image – 11 Photographers, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1982-1991 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 61)
  - The Pinhole Image – 11 Photographers, Virginia Beach Art Center, 1982 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 62)
  - Pinhole Day, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1982 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 63)
  - Juried Exhibition, Light Factory, Charlotte, 1982-1986 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 64)
  - Trends in Color, Focus Gallery, San Francisco, 1983 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 65)
  - Eye Gallery, San Francisco, 1983 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 66)
  - Portraits, Jeffrey Fuller Fine Arts, Philadelphia, 1983 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 67)
  - Exhibitions, University of Rochester, Rochester, 1983-1984 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 68)
  - Handmade Cameras – Contemporary Images, Tyler School of Art, Elkins Park, 1983 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 69)
  - Group Show, Sweet Briar College, Sweet Briar, 1983 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 70)
  - El Día de los Muertos, Galería de la Raza, San Francisco, 1984 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 71)
  - Eye Gallery, San Francisco, 1985 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 72)
  - More than Black and White, Longwood College, Farmville, 1985 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 73)
  - Visionary Pinhole, Book and Show, Images, Cincinnati, 1985-1986 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 74)
  - Senate Offices, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1986-1987 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 75)
  - Virginia Society for the Photographic Arts Virgins, Fredericksburg Center for the Creative Arts, Fredericksburg, 1986 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 76)
  - 2nd Annual Atlanta Photo Salon, Nexus, Atlanta, 1986 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 77)
  - 17th Annual Juried Photo Exhibition, Jewish Community Center, 1986 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 78)
  - 8th Annual Light Images, Chrysler Museum, Norfolk, 1986 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 79)
  - Artists Talk on Art, New York, 1986 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 80)
  - Pinhole Photographs, Southern Light Gallery, Amarillo College, Amarillo, 1987 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 81)
  - Outer Banks to Infinity, Appalachian Environmental Arts Center, Highlands, 1987-1988 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 82)
  - Salon 100, Huntington Galleries, Huntington, 1987 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 83)
  - Points of Departure, Florance Gallery, 1987 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 84)
  - Isis Gallery, 1987 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 85)
  - American Color, New Mexico State University, Los Cruces, 1987-1988 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 86)
  - Radford University, Radford, 1988 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 87)
  - Color Pinhole Photography, Camera Club of New York, New York, 1988 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 88)
  - Art Quest '88, Los Angeles, 1988 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 89)
  - International Pinhole Show, Center for Contemporary Art of Sante Fe, Santa Fe, 1988 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 90)
  - Fine Arts Museum of Long Island, Hempstead, 1988 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 91)
  - Bryn Mawr Conference, Bryn Mawr, 1988 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 92)
  - Peninsula Fine Arts Center, Newport News, 1989 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 93)
  - Images from the Slide Registry, Washington Center for Photography, Washington, D.C., 1989 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 94)
  - The Creative Camera, Dayton Art Institute, Dayton, 1989 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 95)
  - International Pinhole Exhibition, Centre Saidye Bronfman, Montreal, 1989 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 96)
  - 1708 Gallery, 1983-1989 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 97)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980s (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 98)
  - Mary Washington College, Fredericksburg, 1990 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 99)
  - The Pinhole Image – 11 Photographers, Peninsula Fine Arts Center, Newport News, 1990 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 100)
  - Arts Council Airport Show, 1990 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 101)
  - Philadelphia Print Club, Philadelphia, 1990 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 102)
  - Jack Blanton Collection, Randolph-Macon College, Ashland, 1990 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 103)
  - A Gallery, San Francisco, 1990 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 104)
  - Miscellaneous Buckroe Beach, Includes Glover and Willis Pieces, Hampton, 1985-1991 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 105)
  - Images from the Slide Registry, Washington Center for Photography, Washington, D.C., 1991 (Box VA-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 106)
  - 1st Annual Invitational, Hampton University, Hampton, 1992 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 107)
  - Portrait/Self/Portrait, Randolph-Macon College, Ashland, 1992 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 108)
  - Oddball, Artspace, 1993 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 109)
  - Summer Pools, Jack Blanton Fine Arts, 1994 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 110)
  - Points and Perspective, Chastain Art Center, Atlanta, 1994 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 111)
  - E3 Gallery, New York, 1995 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 112)
  - The Museum of the Confederacy, 1995-1996 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 113)
  - Gleaning Light, Photographic Archives, Dallas, 1996 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 114)
  - College of Saint Catherine, St. Paul, 1996 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 115)
  - Virginia Society for the Photographic Arts Folio Exhibition, Greater Reston Arts Center, Reston, 1996 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 116)
  - Civil War Show, East Carolina University, Greenville, 1997 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 117)
  - Timeless Wonders, Museum of Anthropology, Chico, 1997 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 118)
  - Virginia's Photographers, Longwood Center for the Visual Arts, Farmville, 1997 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 119)
  - Peninsula Fine Arts Center, Newport News, 1997 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 120)
  - Southland – Myth, Memory and Artifact, The Art Center, Kinston, 1997 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 121)
  - Coincidence Gallery, 1997 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 122)
  - Picture This – New Photographs from the Collection, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1997 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 123)
  - Southern Memory/Southern Vision, Craven Arts Council and Gallery, New Bern, 1997 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 124)
  - Magiae Naturalis – Pinhole International 2, Lonsdale Gallery, Toronto, 1999 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 125)
  - Carried to the Heart – Faith and Doubt in Contemporary Southern Photography, Millsaps College, Jackson, 1999 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 126)
  - Shadows and Relics, 1708 Gallery, 1999 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 127)
  - The Virtual Civil War, Higginbotham House Museum, Tazewell, 1999 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 128)
  - 1708 Gallery, 1990s (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 129)
  - David Scott Gallery, Toronto, 2000 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 130)
  - Retro Girls, Sweet Briar College, Sweet Briar, 2000 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 131)
  - Longwood Center for the Visual Arts Permanent Collection Photography Comparison, Longwood Center for the Visual Arts, Farmville, 2000 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 132)
  - A Journal of Influences, Eastern Shore Art Center, Fairhope, 2000 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 133)
  - Summer Whites, Glen Allen Cultural Center, Glen Allen, 2000 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 134)
  - Pinholes and Pixels, Emory and Henry College, Emory, 2000 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 135)
  - Paradise, Coincidence Gallery, 2000 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 136)
  - Why Pinhole, Visual Studies Workshop, Rochester, 2001 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 137)
  - Shards of Light, Adirondack Community College, Queensbury, 2001 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 138)
  - Contemporary Photography in Virginia, Art Museum of Western Virginia, Roanoke, 2002 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 139)
  - Lightstruck, Emerge Gallery, Greenville, 2002 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 140)
  - Members Show, Light Factory, Charlotte, 2002 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 141)
  - A History of Photography from the Chrysler Collection, Chrysler Museum, Norfolk, 2002 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 142)
  - Day of the Dead, Three Miles Gallery, 2002 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 143)
  - Small Works Invitational, 1708 Gallery, 2002 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 144)
  - Society for Photographic Education Conference, Virginia Commonwealth University, 2002 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 145)
  - Pierian Springs, Richard Williams, 2002-2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 146)
  - Pure Light – Southern Pinhole Photography, Southeastern Center for Contemporary Art, Winston-Salem, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 147)
  - MinneAperture – An International Exhibition of Contemporary Pinhole Photography, Minnesota Center for Photography, Minneapolis, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 148)
  - 25 x 25, 1708 Gallery, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 149)
  - Think Small2, Artspace, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 150)
  - Longwood College – From Their Collection, Longwood Center for the Visual Arts, Farmville, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 151)
  - Art and Auction Magazine, New York, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 152)
  - River City, Memphis, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 153)
  - Visual Arts Center, Portsmouth, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 154)
  - Lensless Images, 1708 Gallery, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 155)
  - Lensless Images: Contract, 1708 Gallery, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 156)
  - Lensless Images: Costs, 1708 Gallery, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 157)
  - Lensless Images: Gallery Plan, 1708 Gallery, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 158)
- Series 2: Sales and Representation, 1980-2003; VA-02-02
  Box 2 (12 Folders): This series is comprised of information about the sales of Wright's artwork and galleries that represented her from the 1980s to 2003.
  - Sales, 1980s (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 160)
  - Inventory of Art, 1980s? (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 161)
  - Witkin Gallery, New York, 1980-1986 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 162)
  - Ledel Gallery, New York, 1980s (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 163)
  - Reynolds/Minor Gallery, 1980s (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 164)
  - 1708 Auctions, 1991-2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 165)
  - Photo America, 2002 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 166)
  - Hamilton, Lori, 2001 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 167)
  - Holder, Lisa, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 168)
  - Hornsby, Kathy, 2002 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 169)
  - Larson, Rebecca Sexton, 2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 170)
  - Ward, David A., 2002-2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 171)
- Series 3: Curriculum Vitae and Press, 1958-2003; VA-02-03
  Box 2 (1 Folder): This series is comprised of a compendium created by Wright that includes her full artist curriculum vitae and copies of press clippings and essays about her work from 1958 to 2003. This is a copy as Wright retained the original.
  - Willie Anne Wright: Résumé and Documentation from Books, Magazines, Newspapers, 1958-2003 (Box VA-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 172)